Register of the Young Men's Christian Associations Collection, 1917-1920
Hoover Institution Archives
Young Men's Christian Associations Collection,
1917-1920
Young Men's Christian Associations.
61 ms. boxes, 1 oversize box, 15 album boxes, 79 envelopes, 6 linear ft.
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Clippings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to activities of the Young Men's Christian Associations of North America.in the United States and Europe during World War I
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--War work; Europe; United States--Foreign relations; United States--Armed Forces
Container List
- Clippings, Chronological File, 1917-1920.
  - 1917, April - November (Box 1.)
  - 1918, Miscellaneous, January - May (Box 2.)
    - June - July (Box 3.)
    - July - September (Box 4.)
    - September - October (Box 5.)
    - October (Box 6.)
    - October (Box 7.)
    - October (Box 8.)
    - October (Box 9.)
    - October (Box 10.)
    - October and miscellaneous (Box 11.)
    - November (Box 12.)
    - November (Box 13.)
    - November (Box 14.)
    - November (Box 15.)
    - November and miscellaneous and December (Box 16.)
    - December (Box 17.)
    - December (Box 18.)
    - December and miscellaneous (Box 19.)
  - 1919 January
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20.)
    - January (Box 21.)
    - January and miscellaneous (Box 22.)
    - February (Box 23.)
    - February (Box 24.)
    - March (Box 25.)
    - March (Box 26.)
    - March and miscellaneous (Box 27.)
    - April (Box 28.)
    - April (Box 29.)
    - April and miscellaneous (Box 30.)
    - April miscellaneous and May (Box 31.)
    - May (Box 32.)
    - May and June (Box 33.)
    - June (Box 34.)
    - June and miscellaneous (Box 35.)
    - July (Box 36.)
    - July - August (Box 37.)
    - August (Box 38.)
    - September (Box 39.)
    - October (Box 40.)
    - October (Box 41.)
    - October - November (Box 42.)
    - November (Box 43.)
    - November - December (Box 44.)
    - December (Box 45.)
  - 1920, January 1-19 and New York Daily News October 18, 1933. (Box 46.)
- Clippings, Subject File
  - Accounting Department (Box 47.)
  - Active duty
  - Activities, general
  - Advance section
  - Aix-les-Bains
  - American Indians
  - America's calls big business chiefs
  - American Library Association
  - American Expeditionary Forces (A.E.F.) (Box 48.)
    - Debate League, Paris papers
    - Great Britain
    - Remittance Department
    - Russia, North and Archangel
    - Siberia
    - Welfare Organization
    - Y.M.C.A.
  - American Red Cross
  - American Veterans on Leave
  - America's blighty
  - Applications
  - Army Educational Commission
  - Army of occupation
  - Army War Work Council
  - Astor, Mrs. V. and Mrs. Roosevelt
  - Athletics, A.E.F.
  - Athletics Department
  - Athletics, directors and personnel
  - Athletic, enlisting athletes
  - Australian Y.M.C.A.
  - Balloon (Box 49.)
  - Books and Periodical Department
  - Bordeaux Region
  - Bourges Division
  - Boys writing
  - Brest Division
  - British Y.M.C.A.
  - Brussels Detached Area
  - Business Administration Department
  - Boiler plate
  - Boiler plate (Box 50.)
  - Boiler plate (Box 51.)
  - Bulletins to department heads
  - Cafe and Hotel Department
  - Camp Grant
  - Canadian Y.M.C.A.
  - Canteen Department
  - Cartoons, new
  - Casa Del Soldati
  - Casualties
  - Chinese liaison
  - Chocolate
  - Christmas Department
  - Cinema Department (Box 52.)
  - Citations
  - Clark, Mr.
  - Coblenz Division
  - Comrades in service
  - Criticism
  - Czechoslovaks
  - Demobilization
  - Dijon Division
  - Dutch
  - Eagle Hut, London
  - Earn and Give Campaign
  - Educational Department
    - General
    - A.E.F. University; register
  - Employment (Box 53.)
  - Entertainment Department
  - First Combat Division
  - Forestry Units
  - Foyer du Soldat
  - General
  - General history
  - Gievres Division
  - Girls smiles
  - Good long stories
  - Harpist
  - Hike, 150 miles
  - Hospital units
  - Human interest
  - Hut construction
  - Hut Decoration Department
  - Hygiene Department
  - International Committee, Y.M.C.A.
  - Italian Y.M.C.A.
  - Italy
  - Janis, Elsie
  - Jewish Welfare Board
  - Knights of Columbus
  - Leave areas
  - Le Mans Deport Division
  - Library
  - Little, M. (Box 54.)
  - Marseilles Division
  - Miscellaneous and returned
  - Missing soldiers
  - Motor transport
  - National Catholic War Council
  - National War Work
  - Navy
  - Navy and Ocean Transport Department
  - Negro troops
  - News bulletins, classified
  - News releases
  - News service
  - Official commission and other visitors
  - Paris Division
  - Paris Division (Box 55.)
  - Personnel Department
  - Polish work
  - Pontanezen Division
  - Portugal
  - Post exchange
  - Press comments
  - Prisoners of war
  - Publicity Department
  - Publicity (Box 56.)
  - Publicity (Box 57.)
  - Purchasing
  - Recruiting Department
  - Red Cross
  - Relief, France
  - Region seven
  - Religious press
  - Religious work
  - Returned workers
  - Russia
  - Russian liaison
  - Russian work
  - St. Nazaire Division
  - Salvation Army
  - Scholarship story
  - Second Combat Division
  - Seventy-seven room
  - Siberia
  - Sightseeing
  - Soldiers Leave Department
  - Soldiers Leave Department (Box 58.)
  - Speakers Bureau
  - Stationery Department
  - Templeton, H.A.
  - Thirty-Second Combat Division
  - Twenty-Eighth Combat Division
  - Under Fire
  - U.S. home camps and U.S. work
  - War Work Campaign
  - Warm, Miss (Box 59.)
  - Welfare Organizations
  - Welfare societies in A.E.F.
  - Who's Who
  - Why the Y
  - Women's Bureau
  - Work in England
  - Y.M.C.A.
    - General
    - Vaudeville
    - War work
    - Your Sons Safe
    - Bulletins
    - Work at front
- Miscellany
  - Miscellaneous hand-drawn cards (Box 60.)
  - Miscellaneous maps
  - Reports from Adana, Turkey, 1919-1920., 1 vol.
- Oversize Material (Othertype On shelf)
  - Cartoons
  - Exhibit boards, containing photographs, lists, etc.
List of Photographs (Photo envelopes are located in photo file)
- Activities (Othertype A)
- Alabama, Camp McClellan
- Alabama, Camp Sheridan
- American Library Association
- Athletics, Physical Bureau
- Arizona, Southern Department
- Arkansas, Camp Pike
- California (Othertype B)
  - Letterman General Hospital
  - Camp Fremont (Othertype C)
  - Camp Kearney
  - San Diego, Naval Training Camp (Othertype D)
  - San Francisco Open Air Theatre
  - Secretary Daniels at San Francisco Y
  - San Francisco fleet week
  - San Francisco free beds for sailors
  - San Francisco Navy Y.M.C.A.
  - San Francisco Chinese girls, hostesses
  - San Francisco float, parade
  - San Francisco barber shop
  - San Francisco Goat Island
  - San Francisco French lessons
  - San Francisco billiardroom
  - San Francisco canteen
- Campaign Bureau
- Canal Zone
- Colorado, Central Department
- Connecticut
- Construction Bureau (Othertype E)
- Educational work
- Entertainment
- Equipment and supplies
- Florida, Southeastern Department
- Georgia
  - Camp Gordon
  - Camp Hancock (Othertype F)
  - Atlanta, Fort MacPherson
  - Fort Oglethorpe (Othertype G)
- Hawaii
- Hospitals, miscellaneous
- Huts, miscellaneous
- Illinois
  - General
  - Chicago (Othertype H)
  - Camp Grant
  - Camp Logan
  - Rockford
  - Fort Sheridan
- Indiana
  - General
  - Fort Benjamin Harrison
- Iowa (Othertype I)
  - General
  - Camp Dodge
- Kansas
  - General
  - Fort Riley
  - Camp Funston
- Kentucky
  - General
  - Camp Zachary Taylor
  - Camp Thomas
- Louisiana (Othertype J)
  - Camp Beaureguard
  - Southern Department
- Miscellaneous
- Maine
  - Northeastern
  - Fort McKinley
- Maryland
  - Camp Meade
  - General
- Massachusetts
  - Camp Bartlett
  - Camp Devens
  - General (Othertype K)
- Michigan (Othertype L)
  - General
  - Camp Custer
- Minnesota (Othertype M)
  - General
  - Fort Snelling
- Mississippi
  - General
  - Camp Shelby
- Missouri
  - General
  - Jefferson Barracks
- Nebraska (Othertype N)
  - General
  - Fort Omaha
- Negro troops
- New Hampshire
- New Jersey
  - Atlantic City
  - Camp Dix (Othertype O)
  - Hoboken
- New Mexico (Othertype P)
  - Camp Cody
  - Las Vegas, N.M.
  - Southern Department
- New York
  - New York City
  - New York City Eastern Department
  - New York City Eastern Department (Othertype Q)
  - Hospital #41 (Othertype R)
  - Camp Dudley
  - Camp Dudley (Othertype S)
  - Fort Jay
  - Madison Barracks
  - Camp Mills (Othertype T)
  - Fort Niagra
  - Plattsburgh O.T.C.
  - Silver Bay
  - Fort Slocum
  - Camp Syracuse (Othertype U)
  - Camp Upton
- North Carolina
  - Camp Greene
  - Hot Springs
  - Southeastern Department
- Ohio (Othertype V)
  - Columbus Barracks
  - Camp Doniphan
  - Camp Sherman
- Oklahoma
  - Southern Department
- Oregon (Othertype W)
- Pennsylvania
  - Eastern Department
  - Camp Colt (Othertype X)
  - League and Hog Island
  - Philadelphia
- Personnel
- Philippines
- Religious Work Bureau
- Rhode Island, Newport
- Rhode Island, Newport (Othertype Y)
- South America
- South Carolina
  - General
  - Charleston
  - Camp Jackson
  - Camp Wadsworth
- Tennessee
- Texas (Othertype Z)
  - Border
  - Expeditions to troops in Mexico
  - Camp Baker
  - Fort Bliss (Othertype AA)
  - Brownsville
  - Corpus Christi
  - Del Rio
  - Donna (Othertype BB)
  - Eagle Pass
  - El Paso
  - Southern Department, El Paso
  - Fort Worth, Camp Bowie
  - Fort Hancock (Othertype CC)
  - Laredo
  - Llano Grande
  - McAllen
  - MacArthur
  - Pharr (Othertype DD)
  - Southern Department
  - Fort Sam Houston (Othertype EE)
  - San Antonio
  - San Antonio Kelly Field
  - San Antonio
  - Sterling-Ranch
  - Camp Travis (Othertype FF)
  - Waco
  - Camp Wilson
- Transportation Bureau (Othertype GG)
- Transport Service
- U.S. Navy
- Utah
- Vermont, Ethan Allen
- Virginia (Othertype HH)
  - General
  - DuPont Powder Plant
  - Eustis, Camp
  - Camp Lee
  - Fortress Monroe
  - Fort Myer
  - Newport News
  - Norfolk
  - Quantico (Othertype II)
  - Camp Stuart
- Western Department (Othertype JJ)
- West Indies
- Washington, D.C.
- Washington, D.C. (Othertype KK)
- Washington
  - General
  - Camp Lewis
  - Vancouver Barracks
- West Virginia (Othertype LL)
- Wisconsin
- Wyoming, Fort Russell
- Y.W.C.A.
- Miscellaneous - United States, California, Washington, D.C. (Othertype MM-NN)
- England, American boys entertained (Othertype OO)
  - Khaki College
  - Brain Shott
  - Cheltenham
  - Gottenham
  - London
  - Liverpool
  - Stobs (P.O.W.)
  - Warwick Castle
  - Winchester (Rudyard Kipling)
  - Activities (Othertype PP-QQ)
  - Athletics - sports (Othertype RR)
  - Christmas Department
  - Clubs - Officers
  - Clubs - officers (Othertype SS)
  - Educational
  - Entertainment
  - Graves and registration
  - Hospitals (Othertype TT)
  - Hotels
  - Huts
  - Huts (Othertype UU)
  - Navy and transports
- England, miscellaneous (Othertype VV)
- Australian (Othertype WW)
- Canadian
- England and Scotland, Prisoners of War
- England and Scotland, Prisoners of War (Othertype XX)
- New Zealand (Othertype YY)
- Scotland
- Scotland (Othertype ZZ)
- Wales
- Vaidahon Division (Othertype AAA)
  - Christmas Department
  - Hut construction department
  - Personnel Department
- Valencay leave area, clubs
- Vals les bains leave area
- Vannes Division
- Vannes Division, hut construction
- Verdun Division
  - Entertainment Department
  - Hut Construction Department
- Verneuil
- Vierzon
- Vitry
- Warehouse and Shipping Department
- Y.M.C.A. General - U.S. Army
- Y.M.C.A. General, poster slide (Othertype BBB)
- Y.M.C.A. General, women's work
- Y.M.C.A. General
- Activities (Othertype CCC)
- American Library Association (Othertype DDD)
- Athletics (Othertype EEE)
- Campaign Bureau (Othertype FFF)
- Construction Bureau (Othertype GGG)
- Educational work (Othertype HHH)
- Entertainment Bureau (Othertype III)
- Equipment and supplies (Othertype JJJ)
- Hospitals (Othertype KKK)
- Huts (Othertype LLL)
- Miscellaneous (Othertype MMM)
- Negro troops (Othertype NNN)
- Personnel (Othertype OOO)
- Philippines (Othertype PPP)
- Religious work (Othertype QQQ)
- South America (Othertype RRR)
- Transportation Bureau (Othertype SSS)
- United States Navy (Othertype TTT)
- Y.W.C.A. (Othertype UUU)
- Miscellaneous - World War I and II (Othertype VVV-XXX)
- Brownsville, Texas (Othertype f YYY)
- Zapata (Othertype f ZZZ)
- Big Bend, Marfa (Othertype f AAAA)
- Big Bend, Indio (Othertype f BBBB)
- El Paso, Texas (Othertype f CCCC)
- New Mexico and Arizona (Othertype f DDDD)
- Athletics, Southern Department (Othertype f EEEE)
- Mexican border (Othertype f FFFF)
- Texas, miscellaneous (Othertype f GGGG)
- MacArthur, Camp Waco, Texas (Othertype f HHHH)
- Camp Travis (Othertype f IIII)
- Houston and Camp Logan (Othertype f JJJJ)
- San Antonio (Othertype f KKKK)
- Miscellaneous (Othertype f LLLL)
- Miscellaneous (Othertype f MMMM)
- Europe (Othertype f NNNN)
- Europe (Othertype f OOOO)
- Europe (Othertype f PPPP)
- France (Othertype f QQQQ)
- Germany (Othertype f RRRR)
- Belgium and Holand (Othertype f SSSS)
- Bordeaux (Othertype f TTTT)
- France (Othertype f UUUU)
- France (Othertype f VVVV)
- France (Othertype f WWWW)
- History of Sight Seeing Department (Othertype f XXXX-YYYY)
- Huts, France and Germany (Othertype f ZZZZ)
- Huts, France (Othertype fAAAAA)
- Leave Area (Othertype fBBBBB)
- Miscellaneous (Othertype fCCCCC)
- Paris (Othertype fDDDDD)
- Pershing Stadium (Othertype fEEEEE)
- Overseas (Othertype fFFFFF)
- Riviera leave area (Othertype fGGGGG)
- Siberia - I (Othertype fHHHHH)
- Siberia - II (Othertype fIIIII)
- Siberia - III (Othertype fJJJJJ)
- S.O.S (Othertype fKKKKK)
- London, Washington Inn (Othertype fLLLLL)
- Miscellaneous glass plates (Othertype MMMMM-OOOOO)
- Russia (Othertype mPPPPP)
- Russian prisoners of war in Austria (Othertype QQQQQ)
- American prisoners of war in Germany (Othertype RRRRR)
- Savoie and Sarthe regions of France (Othertype SSSSS)